#### Contact

+92 324 4196075 (Mobile) maaz.salman08@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ maazbinsalman (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Entrepreneurship
Project Management

#### Certifications

Advanced SQL for Data Scientists SQL Tips and Tricks for Data Science

Tableau Essential Training
Business Intelligence for Consultants
Supply Chain Principles

# Maaz Bin Salman

Associate Software Engineer | Data Analytics | CureMD | GIKI Lahore District, Punjab, Pakistan

# Summary

Tech Enthusiast | People Oriented | Drive for results | Eager to learn & contribute to my environment

I am currently working in the Data Analytics department at CureMD. I have spent the last 4 years completing my bachelors in Electrical Engineering from a top tier engineering school in Pakistan. Area of expertise include core engineering subjects such as Power Analysis, Communications system along with computer oriented domains including programming (C++, Python, SQL) & Data Visualization tools (Power BI, Tableau).

I have found an acute appreciation of Data Analytics and the impact it generates for a company and the world we live in. I have completed projects using Python, SQL, Power BI, C#, ASP.NET, JS . I have also completed related certifications from IBM, LinkedIn Learning and International Universities on Coursera.

Personally, I enjoy meeting new people and hearing new perspectives.

# Experience

CureMD

8 months

Associate Software Engineer February 2023 - Present (2 months)

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Software Trainee Engineer August 2022 - February 2023 (7 months)

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

-Self Learning, Research and Implementation of Various Technology Stacks including Microsoft SQL Server, Power BI, Tableau, Izenda to help client achieve ultimate satisfaction.

- -Research and Implementation of software workflows to minimize time of resolution of issues.
- -Identification of possible reasons and fixation of bugs for a smooth transition of client to the latest software version.
- -Code Review, Merging and Deployment of latest changes by collaborating with multiple teams for product certifications.

Pak Elektron Limited
Electrical Engineering Intern
August 2021 - September 2021 (2 months)
Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

Design and implementation of commercial transformer (400 KVA)

### PepsiCo

Supply Chain Management Intern June 2021 - August 2021 (3 months) Lahore District, Punjab, Pakistan

Analysing & improve SC process for Key Customers for PepsiCo to achieve efficiency gains (presentation to CEO Pepsi Co)

- 1. First Position among approx. 100 teams
- 2. Proposal include WH Shelf Tagging, use of barcodes in logistics to provide visibility in transit & introduce coherent systems between Pepci Co and its distributors to provide real time inventory situation

#### Quantium

Data Analytics Intern
July 2020 - September 2020 (3 months)

Customer Analytics through Data Preparation, Data Wrangling and visualisation.

## Education

Ghulam Ishaq Khan Institute of Engineering Sciences and Technology

Bachelor of Science - BS, Electrical and Electronics

Engineering · (2018 - 2022)